{
    "id": "e37e930396d64d94b63a64d7c4ba871e",
    "title": "Rather, Would Rather",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He is ......................................",
            "description": "Rather usually goes before articles. ",
            "answers": [
                "rather fool",
                "a rather fool",
                "rather a fool"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ac83ad42b6244e57a7b3b3990eb23f53"
        },
        {
            "question": "That was .................................",
            "description": "Rather can modify nouns. It usually goes before articles if there is no adjective. If there is an adjective it can go before or after articles. ",
            "answers": [
                "rather a good idea",
                "a rather good idea",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "068fe72497aa48fa980d2451aa50ecfd"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ........................ hoping he would leave soon.",
            "description": "Rather is an adverb. It goes after the auxiliary verb and before the main verb. ",
            "answers": [
                "rather were",
                "were rather",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "68e43548e0574ae09a84632d345b5f8d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would prefer to come on Tuesday .................... on Thursday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "rather",
                "would rather",
                "rather than"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c229354b12584cc3ac9c8faf271eeb07"
        },
        {
            "question": "I decided to phone rather than ..................",
            "description": "When the main clause has a to-infinitive, rather than is usually followed by an infinitive without to. An -ing form is also possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "write",
                "writing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6671698576d74854b0967593f6747511"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you rather ..................... here or go home.",
            "description": "Would rather is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "stay",
                "to stay",
                "staying"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ae75bfbb74784382851c9f1ace84accd"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather ....................... something to eat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "to have",
                "having"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "88a276a5da804149b2cbdb6d6588225a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you ...................... me alone.",
            "description": "After would rather, we use a past tense with present or future meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "left",
                "leaving",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e8f0077ed8504aa3878756ac39fc7085"
        },
        {
            "question": "'Should I turn the heating on?' 'I would rather you .....................",
            "description": "After would rather, we use a past tense with present or future meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "not",
                "didn't",
                "hadn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b43e6b9f39414eea86bc5c7930e4d49b"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is important to find new markets rather than .................... new people.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "hire",
                "hiring",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c4853f8709654982ad90905e9da5f060"
        },
        {
            "question": "Rather than ........................ the last of my cash for a meal, I chose to stay hungry.",
            "description": "Spend and spending are both possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "spending",
                "spend",
                "to spend"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b5675d7332ce4b59b5dfc982c0e3ea7a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I would rather you ........................... that. You upset her.",
            "description": "A past perfect tense is used after rather than to talk about past actions. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't say",
                "hadn't said",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9b024e411cc5439ebebafbe52d92b9b5"
        }
    ]
}